# BENJAMIN HERNANDEZ

San Antonio, TX 78228 ♦ (210) 317-8304 ♦ benjamineric2005@gmail.com

## Professional Summary

With over 9 years of experience in the IT industry, I have acquired many years of hands-on and technical project management knowledge with a clear understanding of management duties and responsibilities. My current objective is to apply my leadership skills, organizational skills, and project management skills to help in continuing to lead technology departments mission statement and core values for future successful years to come.

# SKILLS

- Application support
- Strong technical skills
- Ability to work well under pressure.
- Attention to detail.
- Interpersonal and communication skills
- Organization and time management
- Team working skills.
- Management and leadership skills
- Ability to recognize strength in others and delegate accordingly.
- Team leadership
- Conflict resolution
- Team oversight
- Hardware Audit Support
- Active Directory Support
- Migration Support MDMT
- Network Diagnostics (WAP/Cisco)
- Google Administration Support
- Google Administrator I Certified
- Ticketing Systems (SysAid/Zendesk Portal/HEAT)
- Filewave Support
- Smart Console Administration

- Configuration management
- Enterprise applications
- Process implementation
- New employee mentoring
- LAN/WAN troubleshooting
- Excellent problem-solving and analytical skills
- Training delivery
- Process and procedure development
- Inventory control
- Project management
- Technical support (iOS, Windows, Chrome OS)
- Remote Support (TeamViewer, Desktop Remote Desktop Connection, Chrome Remote Desktop, FileWave Remote, DameWare, QuickAssist, Apple Remote, & Smartboard mirroring)
- Mobile Device Management System (Tabpilot/Meraki/COPS)
- Asset Management (WASP, Asset Panda, Samanage, COPS)
- NeverWare (Cloudy Ready systems Administration)
- Printer Support (host/static configuration) (Lock Print MAC familiarity)(Papercut)
- Call Center Support

# WORK HISTORY

#### Field Service Technician I, 08/22/22 - Present

### San Antonio Independent School district – San Antonio, TX

- Provide Tier 1 through 3 technical support service to all technology dept's here at SAISD.
- Provide support to the Superintendent and main office staff including neighboring campuses that range from Kinder to High School level including faculty & Staff technology/software support.
- A liaison between our field services technology team and all other departments in our organization.
- Establishing project specifications and technical direction.
- Creating a framework of technical standards and procedures.
- Overseeing software quality and system modifications.
- Guiding team members with troubleshooting technical issues.
- Analyzing existing field technician operations to identify risks and redundancies.
- Conducting comprehensive assessments to develop solutions.
- Build and maintain the Field Technician Wiki.

#### Field Service Technician II, 07/19/2021 - 08/22/22

#### San Antonio Independent School district - San Antonio, TX

- Provide onsite and remote support for hardware and software performance.
- Troubleshoot complex hardware & software issues.
- Provide technology support for job fairs and board room meetings.
- Provide solutions and fix hardware & software related issues which can include networking issues.

- Being a liaison between and within our technology department to provide and collect day to day updates and report issues. This includes but not limited to providing outage information which can include network issues or testing issues. Picking up and dropping off hardware for repair and to be repaired. Speaking and providing updates to school administration or retrieving information from schools such as network outages to work hand in hand with internal teams to resolve conflicts.
- Create rapport between our technology department and other departments which are not limited to sites such as schools, remote sites, and internal departments.
- Helps other technicians when assistance is needed with their work overload.
- Directly works with the Director & Supervisor of Field Service to tackle real time incidents at the SAISD Central Office.
- Completing tickets in a timely manner and or collecting information if a ticket needs to be escalated.

### Support Services Technology Agent, 05/2016 to 7/09/21

### **KIPP Texas Public Schools** – San Antonio, TX

- Created support documentation using Zendesk that empowered and enabled the user community to extend skills, leverage system features and find resolutions to questions without intervention from the support team.
- Followed up with faculty & staff to ensure optimal customer satisfaction following support engagement and problem resolution.
- Demonstrated professionalism and courtesy with faculty & staff while working to resolve complaints, problems or respond to questions via email, phone, and remote service platforms.
- Assessed system hardware and software and suggested modifications to reduce lag time and improve overall customer satisfaction.
- Helped streamline repair processes and update procedures for support action consistency.
- Responded to support requests from end users and patiently walked individuals through basic troubleshooting tasks.
- Worked with School Leaders & ASL's to resolve hardware & software problems, improve operations, and provide exceptional customer service.
- Resolved conflicts and negotiated agreements between parties to reach win-win solutions to disagreements and clarify misunderstandings.
- Created and managed knowledge base to offer staff and customers immediate informational access to products, services and organization.
- Managed, advised, and trained new support staff in Asset Management, Mobile Device Management, Imaging Devices, Active Directory Account Creations, & Google Admin initiatives and processes.
- Collaborated with a team to define business requirements for organizational processes, achieve productivity standards and adhere to accuracy standards.
- Maintained routine communication with vendors to assess overall satisfaction in the order process for our schools.

#### Pearson Scoring Center Site Technician, 01/2015 to 04/2016

#### **Pearson Education Inc.** – San Antonio, TX

- Configured hardware, devices, and software to set up workstations for employees.
- Removed malware, ransomware and other threats from laptops and desktop systems.
- Responded to support requests from end users and patiently walked individuals through basic troubleshooting tasks.
- Removed and replaced malfunctioning components to correct hardware problems.
- Helped streamline repair processes and update procedures for support action consistency.
- Performed design, layout, and typesetting of publications, office forms and various other projects to optimize designs and production strategies.
- Established logistics policy including mode, carrier and supplier agreements that benefited overall business.

#### **Technical Support Tier III Representative,** 01/2014 to 12/2014

#### **Pearson Education Inc.** – San Antonio, TX

- Worked with the software development team on reported errors and bugs on newly released software and assisted in deployment of release fixes.
- Patched software and installed new versions to eliminate security problems and protect data.
- Removed and replaced malfunctioning components to correct software problems.
- Described Software guidelines & step solutions to customers to assist in problem resolution.
- Engaged end users and answered questions via email, phone, and website live chat and in forums.
- Followed up with clients to ensure optimal customer satisfaction following support engagement and problem resolution.
- Branded products through effective salesmanship and maintained long-term relationships with clients.

# COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT & LEADERSHIP

## Family Life Group Leader (volunteer), 08/2020 to Present

### Westover Hills Church – San Antonio, TX

- Jointly with my spouse, I Co-Lead and organize a life group dedicated to young couples and young families.
- Organize events for couples only, men only, women only or family events for the group to engage and thrive amongst a community of people at similar stages of life with similar goals, values and beliefs.
- Offer & facilitate faith-based couples' mentorship & classes on topics regarding marriage, family, parenting and other key topics that help create a successful family life.
- Create a calendar of events each month to include social events as well as classes & mentorship.
- Communicate with families and couples in person, via text, GroupMe & social media platforms to facilitate community and engagement on a regular basis.

### Small Group Coach (volunteer), 02/2020 to Present

### Westover Hills Church - San Antonio, TX

- Oversee a team of 15-20 adult small group leaders in mentoring, coaching and leading of elementary age children for Sunday morning lessons
- Work closely with new leaders to provide support and training as they acclimate to their roles as small group leaders in which they deliver age appropriate, fun & easy to understand lessons to their small groups of children.
- Meet & collaborate with Kids Ministry Leadership on a regular basis to provide and implement strategies to best engage kids and parents during service times, while also focusing on logistics, safety, scheduling, & attending trainings.
- Organize and plan weekly huddles to execute a successful weekend service while also maintaining an open line of communication for all small group leaders throughout the week for additional training or assistance.

# Athletic Coach (volunteer), 08/2019 to Present

### Westover Hills Church – San Antonio, TX

- Coach and mentor elementary age children's soccer and flag football teams in a faith-based setting.
- Work closely with Sports Director & leadership to organize, collaborate and effectively run the practice and game schedules.
- Engage with parents who are members and nonmembers of the church both in person and thru digital platforms to ensure engagement, oneness and community within the team dynamic.

# **EDUCATION**

# Associate of Applied Science: Information Systems Administration, 12/2013

### Hallmark University - San Antonio, TX

- Member of Alpha Beta Kappa Honor Society
- Awarded President's Award 7 times for maintaining a GPA 4.0
- Graduated with 3.6 GPA

### High School Diploma: 05/2000

St. Gerard Catholic High School - San Antonio, TX

### ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Completing and certifying as Google admin chrome specialist I
- Dell direct certified technician
- Organizing and completing multiple projects under the Supervision of my current Supervisor which include Imaging and installation of over 150 laptops which include upgrading hardware and memory in preparation for the new school year. This also involved making sure all laptops were up to date and current with all Windows and Dell Command updates.
- Being selected amongst my peers to help run and oversee boardroom monthly meetings and ensuring the preparation of technology for those meetings were set up and ready in advance in a timely manner.
- Created a spreadsheet/tutorial document that was used as a guide over all regions during my assignment to lead our SAT SSP migration project within a 2-month time span. This allowed SSP end users to conveniently go in and select their date and time.
- Worked hand in hand with the DFW manager to create, test, and deploy our new asset management platform Samanage. This included successfully deploying the Discovery agent by creating a batch file that was installed on all staff laptops. This allowed devices to be accounted for and audited by not having to go out to every

- school saving time to help other regions with their ticket counts. Assets from our previous asset management system have already been successfully imported and are currently accounted for.
- Managing our current mobile device management (MDM) Securely by Tech Pilot. This includes managing our Apple devices remotely and establishing the Apple configurator 2 tool which will help schools save money by not having to buy directly from Apple Education.
- Selected to provide remote support to our DFW and HOU Region faculty and staff which resulted in diminishing down time during a period of severe outages.
- Saved our IB Testing Administrator 30 hours of manpower by initiating a process through collaborations with the KIPP AUS Manager and Google Admin console. Resulted in avoided hands-on contact to every Chromebook by deploying the audio package to over 128 devices for testing.
- Used innovative techniques to enhance and streamline both the inventory and check-in and check-out process that occurs at the beginning and at the end of the school year for faculty/staff. Result successfully accounting for 95% or more of assets.
- Assisted in rolling out our virtual technology program and creating sites which included date/times for virtual students to pick up devices which include distribution of Chromebooks and hotspots. Continuation of adding all data into our student service portal and maintaining this data up to date which currently keeps clear detailed data of student/device data and the moving of devices internally and externally.